instantprint.co.uk 2019-01-09

# Privacy Policy | instantprint.

#### Protecting your personal details on our website  
Last updated: 18 May 2018

Bluetree Design and Print Limited T/A www.instantprint.co.uk (Registered number 03793442), whose registered office is at Unit 1 Brookfields Park, Manvers Way, Manvers, Rotherham, S63 5DR (“we”, “our”, “us”), knows that you care how information about you is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our Privacy Policy and forms part of our website terms and conditions ("Website Terms"), which you can find here; https://www.instantprint.co.uk/terms-and-conditions.

We believe that it is important to protect your Personal Data, as defined in the Data Protection Act 1998, the General Data Protection Regulations ((EU) 2016/679) and any UK implementing law (“Data Protection Laws”)). We are committed to giving you a personalised service that meets your needs in a way that also protects your privacy.

This Privacy Policy explains how we may collect Personal Data about you. It also explains some of the security measures we take to protect your Personal Data and tells you certain things we will do and not do. You should read this Privacy Policy in conjunction with the Website Terms.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Laws, Bluetree Design and Print Limited. is a data controller and a data processor (depending upon  
what Personal Data it collects and processes from you.

By accepting our Website Terms or by visiting www.instantprint.co.uk ("the Website") you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Should you wish to print a copy of this Privacy Policy for future reference, press ctrl \+ p to do so.

## 1\. Collecting Information

1.1. We may collect Personal Data about you from a number of sources, including the following:

  * 1.1.1. From you when you purchase a service or product from us, which will usually involve creating an instantprint account or a guest account. We will collect your full name, email address, company name (if applicable), billing and delivery details and, if you are creating an instantprint account, you will be asked to provide a password.
  * 1.1.2. From you when you contact us with an enquiry or in response to a communication from us, in which case, this may tell us something about how you use our services.
  * 1.1.3. From documents that are available to the public, such as the electoral register.

1.2. With regard to each of your visits to our site we will automatically collect the following information:

  * 1.2.1. Technical device information, including the device used to access our site (i.e. desktop, mobile or tablet);
  * 1.2.2. Information about your visit, including products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, whether our template designs have been downloaded and whether you have subscribed to our blog and/or mailing lists.

1.3. We do not anticipate collecting any special categories of personal, within the meaning of the Data Protection Laws. For example, information about your health or ethnic origin. However, in the event that we wish to do so, you will be asked to expressly consent to the collection and processing of this Personal Data and are under no obligation to provide such consent.

1.4. Where you provide Personal Data on behalf of a third party, you will ensure that you have all necessary and appropriate consents and notices in place to enable lawful transfer of the Personal Data to us for the duration and purposes of our agreement with you. This will include providing the third party with the information set out in this Privacy Policy and complying with your own obligations under the Data Protection Laws. If you are unable to ensure that you have all necessary and appropriate consents in place, do not transfer or otherwise provider that third party's personal data to us.

## 2\. Using Your Personal Information

2.1. ** ** The Personal Data of our customers is an important part of our business and we shall only use your Personal Data for the following purposes and shall not keep such Personal Data longer than is necessary to fulfil these purposes:

  * 2.1.1. To help us to identify you when you contact us.
  * 2.1.2. To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us.
  * 2.1.3. To allow us to carry out marketing analysis and conduct research (including creating statistical and testing information). We will not, however, use your Personal Data for automated profiling to carry out automated decisions such as evaluating credit without your express consent.
  * 2.1.4. To allow us to contact you (including mail, email, telephone, visit, text or multimedia messages) about products and services offered by us that are similar to those that we have already provided to you or that we have a legitimate interest to contact you about, unless you have asked us not to do so. You can manage your preferences at any time via the preferencing page on our website _ _ or by contacting us using the details set out in clause 6.1. below.
  * 2.1.5. We may check your details with fraud prevention agencies, as further set out in clause 2.4 below.
  * 2.1.6. To notify you about changes to our service.
  * 2.1.7. To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * 2.1.8. To administer the Website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes.
  * 2.1.9. To improve the Website to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * 2.1.10 As part of our efforts to keep the Website safe and secure.

2.2. We will not disclose your Personal Data to any third party except in accordance with this Privacy Policy or with your express consent.

2.3. We may allow other people and organisations to use Personal Data we hold about you in the following circumstances:

  * 2.3.1. Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.
  * 2.3.2. If we, or substantially all of our assets, are acquired or are in the process of being acquired by a third party, in which case Personal Data held by us, about our customers, will be one of the transferred assets.
  * 2.3.3. If we have been legitimately asked to provide information for legal or regulatory purposes or as part of legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings.

2.3.4. If we engage companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Any third parties we may engage are bound by strict contractual provisions with us and only have access to Personal Data needed to perform their functions, and may not use it for other purposes. In addition, they must process the Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as permitted by the Data Protection Laws. The types of third parties that we use include:

  * Contracted courier and delivery companies,
  * Marketing and Market Research companies,
  * Online advertising platforms,
  * Customer Relationship Management software providers,
  * Secure Online payment platforms.

2.4. In connection with any transaction which we enter into with you:

2.4.1. We, and other companies in our group, may from time to time carry out credit and fraud prevention checks with one or more licensed credit reference and fraud prevention agencies. We and they may keep a record of the search. Information held about you by these agencies may be linked to records relating to other people living at the same address with whom you are financially linked. These records will also be taken into account in credit and fraud prevention checks. Information from your application and payment details of your account will be recorded with one or more of these agencies for this purpose.

2.4.2. If you provide false or inaccurate information to us and we suspect fraud, we will record this and may share it with other people and organisations. We, and other credit and insurance organisations, may also use technology to detect and prevent fraud.

2.4.3. If you require further details of the credit agencies and fraud prevention agencies we engage from time to time, please write to our Data Protection Officer using the contact details set out in clause 6.1 below.

3\. Protecting Information

3.1. In accordance with the Data Protection Laws, we adopt strict security measures to protect your Personal Data. 

3.2. All Personal Data you provide to us is stored on our secure servers in the European Economic Area. We will not transfer your Personal Data outside the European Economic Area without your express consent. We also work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.

3.3. We reveal only the last five digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we do however transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing.

3.4. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of Personal Data. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose Personal Data to you.

3.5. It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. If you have any reason to believe that your password may have been accessed by a third party, please contact us as soon as possible and we will take steps to reset that password.

3.6. We will only retain your Personal Data as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements. This will usually be for a period of seven years. To allow you to return to your account to reorder we keep account data for up to 10 years. If an account is inactive for more than 10 years it will be deleted. If you would like us to delete your account details prior to this date please contact us via our customer service teams or via the contact detailsset out in clause 6.1. below.

3.7. To determine the appropriate retention period for Personal Data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your Personal Data, the purposes for which we process your Personal Data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

3.8. In some circumstances we may anonymise your Personal Data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## 4\. The Internet and Cookies

4.1. As stated above, we may occasionally email you about our services and products. We will, however, give you the opportunity to opt-out of that communication in each email. You can also always contact us using the details set out in clause 6.1.

4.2. Please remember that communications over the Internet, such as emails and webmails (messages sent through a website), are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before they are delivered - this is the nature of the Internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of Personal Data that is beyond our reasonable control.

4.3. We may from time to time use 'cookies' on the Website to monitor how people use the Website. This helps us to understand how our customers and potential customers use the Website so we can develop and improve the design, layout and function of the sites. A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive through your browser, to recognise your browser and which records how you have used a website. This means that when you go back to that website, it can give you tailored options based on the information it has stored about your last visit.

4.4. If you do not want us to use cookies, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to tell you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. However, you may not be able to use some of the products or services on the Website without cookies. The ‘Help’ icon on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-ons settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer.

4.5. The cookies that we currently use on the Website are as follows:

Cookie Name| What it does  
---|---  
_#uid | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so we can track how you've used instantprint.co.uk and your behaviour through the site.  
_aw_m_6200 | This allows instantprint.co.uk to track and manage payments of commission to selected publishers.  
_ga | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so we can track how you've used instantprint.co.uk and your behaviour through the site.  
_vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_goal_GOAL_ID | This is generated when a goal is created within Visual Web Optimiser.  
_vis_opt_test_cookie | This is a temporary session cookie generated to detect if the cookies are enabled on the user browser or not.  
_vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_combi | This is generated when users reach a particular combination. This cookie ensures that users see the same variation that they saw on their previous visit to the page.  
_vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_exclude | This is generated when a user is excluded from a VWO test.  
_vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_split | This is generated during a VWO Split URL test.  
_vis_opt_s | This detects if the user is new or returning to a particular VWO test.  
_vis_opt_out | This indicates that the visitor is not part of the VWO test. This cookie is valid for 10 years.  
_vwo_uuid | This generates a unique ID for every visitor and is used for the report segmentation feature in VWO. It also allows you to view data in a more refined manner.  
ASP.NET_SessionId | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so we can track how you've used instantprint.co.uk and your behaviour through the site  
olfsk | This is essential to enabling your use or our website and its features. Without this, services we would provide (such as permitting log-in into the service) cannot be provided.  
SnapABugHistory | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so instantprint.co.uk can provide online support via online chat.  
SnapABugRef | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so instantprint.co.uk can provide online support via online chat.  
SnapABugVisit | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so instantprint.co.uk can provide online support via online chat.  
ciq_visited | This stores a unique user identifier for you, so instantprint.co.uk can present tailored promotions to website visitors.  
_#env | This is used to collect information about your browser. It stores things like screen size and browser type, so we can give you the best experience on instantprint.co.uk  
_#lps | This is used by our marketing partners to track where you came from and how you arrived at instantprint.co.uk  
_#sess | This stores information about a particular visit to instantprint.co.uk and what you've looked at on our site in an individual session. This cookie doesn't store any personal information.  
_#srchist | This stores the history of how you got to instantprint.co.uk.  
_#tsa | This stores the history of how you got to instantprint.co.uk.  
_#vdf | This stores what you've bought on our site while you look at other pages.   
  
4.6. We use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

## 5\. Links

5.1. The Website may include third-party advertising and links to other websites. We do not provide any Personal Data to these advertisers or third-party websites.

5.2. Third-party websites and advertisers, or Internet advertising companies working on their behalf, may also use technology to send (or "serve") the advertisements that appear on the Website directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalise advertising content. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features that they may use, and the information practices of these advertisers and third-party websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please contact them directly for more information about their privacy practices. In addition, the Network Advertising Initiative offers useful information about Internet advertising companies (also called "ad networks" or "network advertisers"), including information about how to opt-out of their information collection. You can find out more information through the website https://www.networkadvertising.org/

5.3. We exclude all liability for loss that you may incur when using these third party websites.

## 6\. Further Information

6.1.If you would like any more information or you have any comments about our Privacy Policy, please either write to us at Data Protection Officer, Unit 1 Brookfields Park, Manvers Way, Manvers, Rotherham, S63 5DR, email us at [DPO@bluetreegroup.co.uk](mailto:DPO@bluetreegroup.co.uk) or telephone us at 0191 2727327.

6.2. We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, in which case we will publish the amended version on the Website. You confirm that we shall not be liable to you or any third party for any change to this Privacy Policy from time to time. It is your responsibility to also check the Website regularly to determine whether this Privacy Policy has changed.

6.3. You can ask us for a copy of this Privacy Policy and of any amended Privacy Policy by contacting us using the details set out in clause 6.1 above. This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Data we hold about individuals. It does not apply to information we hold about companies and other organisations.

6.4. We aim to keep the Personal Data we hold about you accurate and up to date. If you tell us that we are holding any inaccurate Personal Data about you, we will delete it or correct it promptly.

6.5. Please note that we may monitor and record communications with you (including phone conversations and emails) for quality assurance and compliance. You will be advised at the start of your phone conversations with us whether any recording is taking place and whether you are comfortable proceeding on that basis. If not, we will contact you by other means.

## 7\. Your Rights

7.1. The Data Protection Laws give you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. An access request may be subject to an administrative fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. You additionally have the right to ask for your Personal Data to be deleted or to be moved to another provider. These are sometimes referred to the ‘Right to Erasure’ and the ‘Right to Data Portability’.

7.2. Please contact us using the details set out in clause 6.1 if you wish to exercise any of those rights and we will be happy to assist.

7.3. You also have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office if you are unhappy about how we have dealt with your Personal Data. You can find the Information Commissioner’s Office’s website at https://ico.org.uk/
